A Guide to the Typography Ephemera Collection, 1842, 1883-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Typography Ephemera Collection 1842, 1883-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
13061
This collection consists of 19 Hollinger boxes, 8 linear shelf feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred from the Rare Books Division to Manuscripts on May 21, 2004.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of various items concerning the printing business, (19 Hollinger boxes, 8 linear shelf feet), ca. 1842, 1883-1999, and undated. The majority of the content is promotional material from various printing companies: booklets, type samples, publication announcements, bibliographies, woodblocks, printing materials and other such material that serve as samples of the companies' or individuals' work. The organizations represented vary from small businesses to university publishers. Also included are materials concerning the history of printing, printer biographies, paper manufacture and printing equipment.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by company, organization or individual with whom it is affiliated and in chronological order within each folder.
Contents List
- ABBE Press 1952 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Adagio Press 1964-1983 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Advertisements: Posters, Broadsides, Trade Cards, Etc. 1883-1904 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Advertising Typographers of America, Inc. 1948-1963 (Box-folder 1:4)
- The Alcuin Press 1932 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Alden Press 1970 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Aldine Press 1973 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Allen Press 1943-1949, n.d. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Allen Holme Press c. 1964 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Amateur Printer's Club / Publications 1956-1958 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Amberger, F.L. 1940 (Box-folder 1:11)
- American Institute of Graphic Arts 1942-1973 (Box-folder 1:12)
- American Publishing 1965-1975 (Box-folder 1:13)
- American Type Founders Company 1939,1954, n.d. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Amsterdam Continental n.d. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Angelica Press 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1:16)
- Announcements / Births and Marriages 1969-1973 (Box-folder 1:17)
- Announcements of Books Published (Not in USA) 1963-1964, n.d. (Box-folder 1:18)
- Anthoensen Press [The Old Southworth-Anthoensen Press], Portland, Maine 1936-1986 (Box-folder 2:1)
- The Antique Press n.d. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Anvil Press 1981,1984, n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Arden Park, Press of 1976 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Aries Press 1926-1927 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Arion Press 1973-1982 (Box-folder 2:6)
- Arion Press 1984-1987, n.d. (Box-folder 2:7)
- Arkham House 1968 (Box-folder 2:8)
- The Artful Dodger 1961 (Box-folder 2:9)
- Arts Action Press 1975 (Box-folder 2:10)
- At the Sign of the Chorobates 1931 (Box-folder 2:11)
- Attic Press 1949-1977, n.d. (Box-folder 2:12)
- Augustin, J.J., Printer - Calendar of Ideas 1938-1940 (Box-folder 2:13)
- The Autobiography of a Book n.d. (Box-folder 2:14)
- Ayer, Edward Everett 1927 (Box-folder 2:15)
- Bahr, Leonard F. 1957 (Box-folder 2:16)
- Barrow Lab, Richmond, Virginia (Lamination) 1939-1969 (Box-folder 2:17)
- Baskerville, John 1941 (Box-folder 3:1)
- Baskerville Type 1931 (Box-folder 3:2)
- Battell Chappel 1963 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Bauer Type Foundry 1937-1941 (Box-folder 3:4)
- Beaverdam Press 1981 (Box-folder 3:5)
- Beehive Press n.d. (Box-folder 3:6)
- Belch, David 1972 (Box-folder 3:7)
- Bennett, Paul A. 1960 (Box-folder 3:8)
- Berliner, Harold 1988 (Box-folder 3:9)
- Bibles 1949-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 3:10)
- Bice Press 1976 (Box-folder 3:11)
- Bickham, George 1970, 1976 (Box-folder 3:12)
- Brick Row Book Shop 1986 (Box-folder 3:13)
- Bieler Press 1978, n.d. (Box-folder 3:14)
- Binders, Guild of Women 1898 (Box-folder 3:15)
- Binding: Edges Gauffered and Gilded 1950-1976, n.d. (Box-folder 3:16)
- Binding, Prices 1951 (Box-folder 3:17)
- Bird and Bull Press 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 3:18)
- Black Cat Press 1962-1968 (Box-folder 3:19)
- Black Mesa Press 1978 (Box-folder 3:20)
- The Black Pennell press 1985 (Box-folder 3:21)
- Black Sparrow Press 1968-1970 (Box-folder 3:22)
- Black Vine Press 1956 (Box-folder 3:23)
- Blackwell's 1938-1953 (Box-folder 3:24)
- Blackwood Press 1958 (Box-folder 3:25)
- Blue Ox Press 1937 (Box-folder 3:26)
- The Bobcat Press (Made and Sold by Richard Hicks) 1976 (Box-folder 3:27)
- Bodini Press 1976 (Box-folder 3:28)
- The Bodley Head 1896 (Box-folder 3:29)
- Bond Wheelwright Company 1949 (Box-folder 3:30)
- The Book Club of California (2 Folders) 1973-1987 (Box-folder 3:31)
- Book Design 1929 (Box-folder 3:32)
- Book Illustration 1948, n.d. (Box-folder 3:33)
- Book Marks n.d. (Box-folder 3:34)
- Book of the Month Club 1951 (Box-folder 3:35)
- Book Builders of Boston 1957-1961 (Box-folder 3:36)
- Book Plates 1937-1978, n.d. (Box-folder 3:37)
- Brad Stephens & Co. n.d. (Box-folder 4:1)
- Bradford, William: Printer 1963 (Box-folder 4:2)
- Brass Rubbing n.d. (Box-folder 4:3)
- Brayers Club 1946 (Box-folder 4:4)
- Bremer Presse 1928 (Box-folder 4:5)
- Bromer, Anne and David 1979 (Box-folder 4:6)
- Brown, Don and Kay 1962 (Box-folder 4:7)
- Brussel-Smith n.d. (Box-folder 4:8)
- Bulletin - Buffalo Club of Printing House Craftsmen 1953 (Box-folder 4:9)
- The Bunny Press 1965 (Box-folder 4:10)
- Business Cards n.d. (Box-folder 4:11)
- Calkins, Earnest Elmo 1952 (Box-folder 4:12)
- Calle del Cristo 1958 (Box-folder 4:13)
- Campane 1962-1963 (Box-folder 4:14)
- Cape Goliard Press 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4:15)
- Carey and Claridge LTD 1971-1972 (Box-folder 4:16)
- Carnegie Institute, Laboratory Press 1924-1926 (Box-folder 4:17)
- Cary, John 1924 (Box-folder 4:18)
- Cary, Melbert B. 1978 (Box-folder 4:19)
- The Castle Press n.d. (Box-folder 4:20)
- Caxton, William 1976 (Box-folder 4:21)
- Caxton Press - New Delhi, India n.d. (Box-folder 4:22)
- Censorship 1953 (Box-folder 4:23)
- Chamberlain Press 1982-1987 (Box-folder 4:24)
- Chappell, Warren - Clemons Dedication, Copy 1 1982 (Box-folder 4:25)
- Chappell, Warren - Clemons Dedication, Copy 2 1982 (Box-folder 4:26)
- Chappell, Warren - Lettering... n.d. (Box-folder 4:27)
- Chappell, Warren - Type Specimen 1948 (Box-folder 4:28)
- Chappell, Warren - Woodcut by Fritz Kredel n.d. (Box-folder 4:29)
- The Chappell Movement 1957 (Box-folder 4:30)
- The Charles Bruning Company c. 1955 (Box-folder 4:31)
- Chelonidae Press (See also: Ephemera: Oversized) 1982-1985 (Box-folder 4:32)
- Children's Books 1986 (Box-folder 4:33)
- Chimera 1953, 1986 (Box-folder 4:34)
- Chiswick Press 1901 (Box-folder 4:35)
- Christmas Cards 1925-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 4:36)
- Christmas Cards 1925-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 4:37)
- Christmas Greetings (Miscellaneous 1941-1965, n.d. (Box-folder 4:38)
- City Lights Book Sellers and Publishers 1969 (Box-folder 5:1)
- Club of Printing House Craftsmen 1953 (Box-folder 5:2)
- Cobb Shinn 1958 (Box-folder 5:3)
- Cockescraw Press 1963 (Box-folder 5:4)
- Colish, A. n.d. (Box-folder 5:5)
- The Collector 1953-1954 (Box-folder 5:6)
- Colophon 1931-1944 (Box-folder 5:7)
- Colorado College Press c. 1980 (Box-folder 5:8)
- Columbia University Book Arts Press 1983 (Box-folder 5:9)
- Composing Room Inc. 1937-1967 (Box-folder 5:10)
- Composing Room Inc. 1937-1967 (Box-folder 5:11)
- Copeland and Day 1897 (Box-folder 5:12)
- Crabgrass Press 1963 (Box-folder 5:13)
- Cranium Press 1972 (Box-folder 5:14)
- Creative Typographers 1949-1950 (Box-folder 5:15)
- Crepuscular Press n.d. (Box-folder 5:16)
- Cryptography 1973 (Box-folder 5:17)
- Cubicle Press 1962 (Box-folder 5:18)
- Cuckoo Hill Press 1962 (Box-folder 5:19)
- Cummington Press 1948-1975 (Box-folder 5:20)
- Cuneo Press 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5:21)
- Curwen Press 1964-1981 (Box-folder 5:22)
- Cushing, Frank M. 1961 (Box-folder 5:23)
- D. Albert Brown n.d. (Box-folder 5:24)
- Da Boll, Raymond - Calligrapher 1959-1961 (Box-folder 5:25)
- Dahlstrom, Grant 1950 (Box-folder 5:26)
- Dakota Press 1980 (Box-folder 5:27)
- Danish Book Printing, Sixty Years of 1949 (Box-folder 5:28)
- The Dard Hunter Paper Museum 1962 (Box-folder 5:29)
- David, Ismar 1953 (Box-folder 5:30)
- Darison, Dave 1966 (Box-folder 5:31)
- Dawson's Book Shop 1980-1983 (Box-folder 5:32)
- Dead Language Press n.d. (Box-folder 5:33)
- Deberny et Peignot c. 1951 (Box-folder 6:1)
- DeBury, Richard 1951, n.d. (Box-folder 6:2)
- Deighton, Bell & Company n.d. (Box-folder 6:3)
- De Pol, John 1953-1962 (Box-folder 6:4)
- Derrydale Press 1941-1951 (Box-folder 6:5)
- The Deux Magots Press 1931 (Box-folder 6:6)
- Design and Paper 1952 (Box-folder 6:7)
- Detroit Public Library n.d. (Box-folder 6:8)
- Dial Press 1966 (Box-folder 6:9)
- Dickman, O. Alfred 1962 (Box-folder 6:10)
- Dietz August (and Dietz Press; Richmond, VA) 1921-1928 (Box-folder 6:11)
- Dieu Donne Press and Paper 1982 (Box-folder 6:12)
- A Different Drummer 1958-1959 (Box-folder 6:13)
- Dogwood Press 1948 (Box-folder 6:14)
- Duensing, Paul Hayden 1964 (Box-folder 6:15)
- Duschnes, Philip C. (Printer) 1946 (Box-folder 6:16)
- Dwiggins, W.A. 1944-1987 (Box-folder 6:17)
- Earl & Ivana Kallemeyn Printers 1981 (Box-folder 6:18)
- Early Printing 1953-1978 (Box-folder 6:19)
- The Echo 1962 (Box-folder 6:20)
- Eden Hill Press n.d. (Box-folder 6:21)
- Elliot, Jim + Kibbee, Wallace 1955 (Box-folder 6:22)
- Empire Printing Company n.d. (Box-folder 6:23)
- Endgrain Press 1951 (Box-folder 6:24)
- End Papers (Examples) n.d. (Box-folder 6:25)
- Engravings 1949, 1975 (Box-folder 6:26)
- Enschede en Lonen, Joh. 1965 (Box-folder 6:27)
- Eucalyptus Press 1939 (Box-folder 6:28)
- Europa Publications 1966 (Box-folder 6:29)
- Examples of Printing 1956 (Box-folder 6:30)
- Ex Ophidia 1987 (Box-folder 6:31)
- Far Afield 1963 (Box-folder 6:32)
- Favil Press 1949 (Box-folder 6:33)
- The Feather Duster 1944 (Box-folder 6:34)
- Ferrer, Albert 1987 (Box-folder 7:1)
- Fischer Press 1964 (Box-folder 7:2)
- Fleck, Robert 1900-1904 (Box-folder 7:3)
- Fleming, Guy 1977 (Box-folder 7:4)
- Folio Society 1950, 1978 (Box-folder 7:5)
- Fordham University Press n.d. (Box-folder 7:6)
- Four Ducks Press 1958, 1962 (Box-folder 7:7)
- Four Winds Press n.d. (Box-folder 7:8)
- Fowler, Alfred n.d. (Box-folder 7:9)
- Franklin, Typothetae of Chicago 1915 (Box-folder 7:10)
- Fraser, John G. 1961 (Box-folder 7:11)
- Frederick W. Schmidt, Inc. 1961-1967 (Box-folder 7:12)
- Friday Market 1961 (Box-folder 7:13)
- Frigate Press 1966 (Box-folder 7:14)
- The Gardyloo Press 1982 (Box-folder 7:15)
- Garden View Press 1955, 1965 (Box-folder 7:16)
- Gehenna Press 1971-1975 (Box-folder 7:17)
- Georgian Press 1958 (Box-folder 7:18)
- Gid, Denise and Raymond 1973 (Box-folder 7:19)
- Giesey, Paul O. 1960 (Box-folder 7:20)
- Goines, David Lance 1981 (Box-folder 7:21)
- Golden Cockerel Press 1934-1954 (Box-folder 7:22)
- The Golden Cross Press 1960 (Box-folder 7:23)
- Golden Hind Press 1942-1959 (Box-folder 7:24)
- Good Book Press c. 1985 (Box-folder 7:25)
- Goudy, Frederic W. 1948-1966 (Box-folder 7:26)
- Grabhorn Press 1961-1987 (Box-folder 7:27)
- Grabhorn, Robert (Fine Printing) 1970-1975 (Box-folder 7:28)
- Grace Hoper Press 1960-1983 (Box-folder 8:1)
- Graduate Magazine Press / University of Kansas 1904-1905 (Box-folder 8:2)
- Graphic Arts Club 1934 (Box-folder 8:3)
- Gravesend Press 1953-1957 (Box-folder 8:4)
- Greywolf Press 1976 (Box-folder 8:5)
- Greenwood Press 1967-1973 (Box-folder 8:6)
- Gregynog Press 1976, 1983 (Box-folder 8:7)
- The Griddle Press 1956, 1964 (Box-folder 8:8)
- Grimaikin Press 1959 (Box-folder 8:9)
- The Guidon 1953 (Box-folder 8:10)
- Guild of Book Workers n.d. (Box-folder 8:11)
- Gutchen, R. 1976 (Box-folder 8:12)
- Gutenberg 1925-1940 (Box-folder 8:13)
- Gutenberg Bible (Reprint) 1930-1950 (Box-folder 8:14)
- Gutenberg Museum 1973 (Box-folder 8:15)
- Gwasg Gregynog 1976-1984 (Box-folder 8:16)
- Hackett, Edmond Byrne 1936-1938 (Box-folder 8:17)
- Hamilton Press 1962 (Box-folder 8:18)
- Hammer Creek Press 1951 (Box-folder 8:19)
- Hampshire Typothetae n.d. (Box-folder 8:20)
- Hantke, Gary n.d. (Box-folder 8:21)
- Hardacre, Kenneth n.d. (Box-folder 8:22)
- Hart, Ruth and James 1948-1979 (Box-folder 8:23)
- Harvard 1963 (Box-folder 8:24)
- Hawthorne House n.d. (Box-folder 8:25)
- Heintzemann Press 1913 (Box-folder 8:26)
- Helen Gentry Press 1934 (Box-folder 8:27)
- The Hell Box n.d. (Box-folder 8:28)
- Hendrickson, James 1948 (Box-folder 8:29)
- The Heritage Club n.d. (Box-folder 8:30)
- Heritage of the Graphic Arts Series n.d. (Box-folder 8:31)
- Heritage Printers 1957-1958 (Box-folder 8:32)
- The Herity Press 1957, 1959 (Box-folder 8:33)
- Hertzog, Carl 1960, n.d. (Box-folder 8:34)
- Heyeck, Robin 1982 (Box-folder 8:35)
- The Heyeck Press 1981-1984 (Box-folder 9:1)
- High Loft 1979 (Box-folder 9:2)
- Hippogryph Press 1954 (Box-folder 9:3)
- Hirschfield Press 1953 (Box-folder 9:4)
- Hoflund-Schmidt Typographic Service 1953, n.d. (Box-folder 9:5)
- Home Shop Printers 1961 (Box-folder 9:6)
- Hornbook Press 1947 (Box-folder 9:7)
- Hoyem, Andrew 1934 (Box-folder 9:8)
- Hughey, Michael W. - Calligrapher 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 9:9)
- Hutchinson, Bradley 1987 (Box-folder 9:10)
- Hutchinson, Eric 1978 (Box-folder 9:11)
- Impressions 1957 (Box-folder 9:12)
- Imprint Society 1969-1973 (Box-folder 9:13)
- Incunabula 1970-1977 (Box-folder 9:14)
- International Allied Printing Trades Association 1963 (Box-folder 9:15)
- International Association of Printing House Craftsmen 1955 (Box-folder 9:16)
- International Center for the Typographic Arts 1965 (Box-folder 9:17)
- Interstate Printing Corporation n.d. (Box-folder 9:18)
- International Printing Machinery and Allied Trades Exhibitions 1963 (Box-folder 9:19)
- International Typeface Corporation 1985 (Box-folder 9:20)
- Invitations 1975 (Box-folder 9:21)
- Ironwood Press Inc. 1972 (Box-folder 9:22)
- Isaiah Thomas Printing Office 1952 (Box-folder 9:23)
- Ishill, Joseph 1955 (Box-folder 9:24)
- The Isis Press 1983 (Box-folder 9:25)
- J.M. Bundscho Inc. 1952-1954 (Box-folder 9:26)
- James, William - Association 1976 (Box-folder 9:27)
- Janus Press 1975-1986 (Box-folder 9:28)
- Jno Hanna and Sons 1964 (Box-folder 9:29)
- Joanna Western Mills Company 1969 (Box-folder 9:30)
- John Knox Press, Richmond 1968 (Box-folder 9:31)
- John Roberts Press 1965 (Box-folder 9:32)
- Johnston, Paul 1933 (Box-folder 9:33)
- Judd and Detweiler 1949 (Box-folder 9:34)
- Jung, Theodor 1953-1954 (Box-folder 9:35)
- Just Our Type 1963-1966 (Box-folder 9:36)
- Kairos Press 1987 (Box-folder 9:37)
- Katydid Press 1961 (Box-folder 9:38)
- Kelmscott Press 1965-1976 (Box-folder 9:39)
- Kikendall, Harry n.d. (Box-folder 9:40)
- Kitemaug Press n.d. (Box-folder 10:1)
- Kennedy, Lawton -Printer 1954-1978 (Box-folder 10:2)
- The King and Queen Press 1964 (Box-folder 10:3)
- The King Library Press 1975-1986 (Box-folder 10:4)
- Kingsport Press n.d. (Box-folder 10:5)
- Klingspor Type Founders n.d. (Box-folder 10:6)
- Kredel, Fritz n.d. (Box-folder 10:7)
- Lakeside Press 1951-1961 (Box-folder 10:8)
- Lankes, J.J. n.d. (Box-folder 10:9)
- Lanston Monotype Machine 1956-1965 (Box-folder 10:10)
- Lantern Press 1961 (Box-folder 10:11)
- Lasky Company n.d. (Box-folder 10:12)
- Lauck, C. Harold 1953-1965 (Box-folder 10:13)
- Leather for Bookbinding n.d. (Box-folder 10:14)
- Leather for Bookbinding (Samples) n.d. (Box-folder 10:15)
- L'esperance, Sivertson and Beran 1948, 1951 (Box-folder 10:16)
- Libanus Press 1987 (Box-folder 10:17)
- Lime Kiln Press 1972-1978 (Box-folder 10:18)
- Lime Rock Press 1980-1981 (Box-folder 10:19)
- Linden, James n.d. (Box-folder 10:20)
- Linotype News 1955 (Box-folder 10:21)
- The Little Press 1954-1965 (Box-folder 10:22)
- Loftus, Mark - Typographer n.d. (Box-folder 11:1)
- The Los Angeles Club of Printing House Craftsmen, Inc. 1954, 1961 (Box-folder 11:2)
- Los Angeles State College Press 1963 (Box-folder 11:3)
- The Lucky Dog 1940-1942 (Box-folder 11:4)
- The MIT Press n.d. (Box-folder 11:5)
- McGraw-Phillips n.d. (Box-folder 11:6)
- Manhattan Art Press n.d. (Box-folder 11:7)
- Mainz Psalter n.d. (Box-folder 11:8)
- Marchbanks Press 1942-1958 (Box-folder 11:9)
- Marigold Press 1955 (Box-folder 11:10)
- Marquardt and Company n.d. (Box-folder 11:11)
- Martin, Jessie and Gordon 1955 (Box-folder 11:12)
- McCowat - Mercer Press n.d. (Box-folder 11:13)
- Menhaden Press 1982 (Box-folder 11:14)
- Mergenthaler Linotype Company 1934-1935 (Box-folder 11:15)
- Mermaid Press 1957-1964 (Box-folder 11:16)
- Merrion Press (Islamic Calligraphics) 1976 (Box-folder 11:17)
- The Merrymount Press 1903-1949 (Box-folder 11:18)
- Michael, John and Jean 1979 (Box-folder 11:19)
- Middle Hill Press 1918-1872 (Box-folder 11:20)
- Miles Gallery Proof Press n.d. (Box-folder 11:21)
- Milliken, Harry N. 1964 (Box-folder 11:22)
- Miscellaneous 1897-1959 (Box-folder 11:23)
- Mohawk Smoke Signal 1954 (Box-folder 11:24)
- Morgan Press 1959 (Box-folder 11:25)
- Mosher, Thomas B. ("Private" Press) (Fine Printing) 1895-1914 (Box-folder 11:26)
- Music n.d. (Box-folder 11:27)
- Mystic River Press 1979 (Box-folder 11:28)
- Nash, John Henry (Printer) 1926-1973 (Box-folder 11:29)
- National Book League of Great Britain n.d. (Box-folder 11:30)
- New Jersey Type Founders n.d. (Box-folder 12:1)
- New York Chappel 1959-1960 (Box-folder 12:2)
- New York Type Directors Club n.d. (Box-folder 12:3)
- The Newark Craftsman 1952 (Box-folder 12:4)
- Nonesuch Press 1924-1963 (Box-folder 12:5)
- Non Pareil Press n.d. (Box-folder 12:6)
- The Noonday Press n.d. (Box-folder 12:7)
- The Norman Press n.d. (Box-folder 12:8)
- North Point Press 1980-1985 (Box-folder 12:9)
- Northwoods Press 1978-1979 (Box-folder 12:10)
- The Nova Press 1959-1966 (Box-folder 12:11)
- The Occasional Press 1963 (Box-folder 12:12)
- Offhand Press 1961 (Box-folder 12:13)
- Officina Brindabella 1986 (Box-folder 12:14)
- Ogg, Oscar 1963, 1965 (Box-folder 12:15)
- Oliphant Press 1970-1972 (Box-folder 12:16)
- Olms Press n.d. (Box-folder 12:17)
- Optik (Contemporary Graphics) n.d. (Box-folder 12:18)
- Oriole Press 1939-1961 (Box-folder 12:19)
- Oroboro Press 1965 (Box-folder 12:20)
- Ostroot and Williamson 1951 (Box-folder 12:21)
- Overbrook Press 1935-1984 (Box-folder 12:22)
- Oyez 1976 (Box-folder 12:23)
- Paper, History of 1972 (Box-folder 12:24)
- Paper For Modern Printing 1910-1961 (Box-folder 12:25)
- Paper Specimens 1946 (Box-folder 13:1)
- Paradise Press n.d. (Box-folder 13:2)
- Pardoe, F.E. 1963 (Box-folder 13:3)
- Parnussus: Poetry in Review 1972 (Box-folder 13:4)
- The Pastime Printer 1957 (Box-folder 13:5)
- Paycheck Press 1976 (Box-folder 13:6)
- Peacocks Press n.d. (Box-folder 13:7)
- Pear Tree Press 1937, 1958 (Box-folder 13:8)
- Pease Press 1961 (Box-folder 13:9)
- The Peccary Press 1986 (Box-folder 13:10)
- Pendomer Press n.d. (Box-folder 13:11)
- Penmaen Press 1976 (Box-folder 13:12)
- Pennyroyal Press 1976-1986 (Box-folder 13:13)
- Penstemon Press n.d. (Box-folder 13:14)
- Penteyegram Press 1975 (Box-folder 13:15)
- Peregrine Press 1951-1958 (Box-folder 13:16)
- Perishable Press 1976 (Box-folder 13:17)
- Peter Pauper Press 1936-1950 (Box-folder 13:18)
- Petrarch Press 1989 (Box-folder 13:19)
- Petty, Harvey 1957 (Box-folder 13:20)
- Pfutser and Tinker Press 1958 (Box-folder 13:21)
- Philmac Typographers n.d. (Box-folder 13:22)
- Philter Press 1961 (Box-folder 13:23)
- Photo Lettering, Inc. 1961-1962 (Box-folder 13:24)
- Photo Lettering, Inc. 1962-1964 (Box-folder 13:25)
- Photo Typositor Film Alphabets n.d. (Box-folder 13:26)
- Pickering Press 1953-1956 (Box-folder 13:27)
- Pigeonhole Press 1957 (Box-folder 13:28)
- Pittsburgh Bibliophiles 1962-1970 (Box-folder 14:1)
- Plain Wrapper Press 1971-1980 (Box-folder 14:2)
- Plantin, Christophe -Museum Postcard n.d. (Box-folder 14:3)
- Pomegranate Press 1974 (Box-folder 14:4)
- The Pony Barn Press 1946 (Box-folder 14:5)
- Popinjay Press 1968 (Box-folder 14:6)
- Possumus Press n.d. (Box-folder 14:7)
- Posthorn Press 1986 (Box-folder 14:8)
- Pourparler n.d. (Box-folder 14:9)
- Powers Private Press 1956-1962 (Box-folder 14:10)
- Prairie Press 1939-1961 (Box-folder 14:11)
- Pratt, Marjorie Bates n.d. (Box-folder 14:12)
- Press In Tuscany Alley 1982-1984 (Box-folder 14:13)
- Presso Arcangelo Strambi Tipografo 1842 (Box-folder 14:14)
- Press of Apple Tree Alley 1983-1987 (Box-folder 14:15)
- Press of the Iron Horse 1953 (Box-folder 14:16)
- Press of the Night Owl 1965 (Box-folder 14:17)
- Presses 1980 (Box-folder 14:18)
- Print Collecting n.d. (Box-folder 14:19)
- Printers 1976 (Box-folder 14:20)
- The Printery 1973 (Box-folder 14:21)
- Printing, History and Background 1963-1976 (Box-folder 14:22)
- Printing in Virginia, Misc. 1900-1965 (Box-folder 14:23)
- Printing, It's Start in America 1939 (Box-folder 14:24)
- The Printing Machinery Company n.d. (Box-folder 14:25)
- Printing Presses n.d. (Box-folder 14:26)
- Privateer Press 1957-1961 (Box-folder 14:27)
- Puppet Press n.d. (Box-folder 14:28)
- Pynson Printers 1937, 1939, 1955 (Box-folder 15:1)
- Pyracantha Press 1984-1985 (Box-folder 15:2)
- Quest 1958-1960 (Box-folder 15:3)
- Rampant Lions Press 1974-1999 (Box-folder 15:4)
- Ratdolt, Erhard 1985 (Box-folder 15:5)
- Reagh, Patrick n.d. (Box-folder 15:6)
- Rebis Press 1976, 1981 (Box-folder 15:7)
- Red Angel Press 1980 (Box-folder 15:8)
- Red Hen Press 1988 (Box-folder 15:9)
- Red Path Press 1960-1961 (Box-folder 15:10)
- Reed, Phillip 1949-1956 (Box-folder 15:11)
- River Hill Press 1959 (Box-folder 15:12)
- The River Hill Printer 1958 (Box-folder 15:13)
- Riverside Press 1962 (Box-folder 15:14)
- Rittenhouse, Jack n.d. (Box-folder 15:15)
- Robertson, Carolyn and James 1984 (Box-folder 15:16)
- Rochester Institute of Technology School of Printing 1963-1980 (Box-folder 15:17)
- Roger Ascham Press 1975-1981 (Box-folder 15:18)
- Rogers, Bruce 1953-1957 (Box-folder 15:19)
- Rollins, Carl 1963 (Box-folder 15:20)
- The Rose Valley Press 1963 (Box-folder 15:21)
- Roxburghe Club 1932 (Box-folder 15:22)
- Rudge, W.E. 1926-1951 (Box-folder 15:23)
- The Rumford Press 1948 (Box-folder 15:24)
- Russell, R.H. (New York Publisher) 1897-1899 (Box-folder 15:25)
- Rydal Press 1936, 1938, 1986 (Box-folder 15:26)
- Sahlin, Axel E. 1954 (Box-folder 15:27)
- St. Dominic's Press 1929 (Box-folder 15:28)
- Salmon, Maurice 1982-1983 (Box-folder 15:29)
- San Francisco Club of Printing House Craftsmen 1956 (Box-folder 15:30)
- The Sandstone Press 1981 (Box-folder 15:31)
- Sans Souci Press 1961-1965 (Box-folder 15:32)
- Santa Lucia Press 1981 (Box-folder 15:33)
- The Sarabande Press 1985 (Box-folder 15:34)
- Scarab Press 1972 (Box-folder 15:35)
- The Scarlet Cockerel 1940-1972 (Box-folder 15:36)
- Scolar Press 1972 (Box-folder 15:37)
- The Scorpio Press 1980 (Box-folder 15:38)
- Scott, Foresman and Company 1961 (Box-folder 15:39)
- Scribner Press n.d. (Box-folder 15:40)
- Sea Pen Press and Papermill 1978-1981 (Box-folder 15:41)
- Seattle Club of Printing House Craftsmen 1936 (Box-folder 16:1)
- Seed Corn c.1947-1957 (Box-folder 16:2)
- Sentinel Printing c.1936 (Box-folder 16:3)
- Sez Higgins-McArthur Company 1948-1949 (Box-folder 16:4)
- Shady Acre Private Press 1960 (Box-folder 16:5)
- Shady Tree Press 1957-1963 (Box-folder 16:6)
- Shakespeare Head Press 1933 (Box-folder 16:7)
- Shaull, Randall -Designer c. 1910 (Box-folder 16:8)
- Siamese Standpipe 1964 (Box-folder 16:9)
- Sign of the Priceless Pearl 1963 (Box-folder 16:10)
- Signet Press 1955 (Box-folder 16:11)
- Skelton's Press Ltd. 1983 (Box-folder 16:12)
- Smithsonian Institution National Museum of American History 1983, 1986 (Box-folder 16:13)
- Society of Bookcraft 1948 (Box-folder 16:14)
- The Society of Printer's of Boston 1953-1960 (Box-folder 16:15)
- Society of Typographic Arts 1947-1968 (Box-folder 16:16)
- Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc. 1965-1974 (Box-folder 16:17)
- The Southworth Press 1933 (Box-folder 16:18)
- Spare Moments Press n.d. (Box-folder 16:19)
- Spectator 1961-1962 (Box-folder 16:20)
- Spiral Press 1952-1961 (Box-folder 16:21)